A Guide to the Stanford Moore papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA111
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reprints, 1940-1982; 9
  - "Susceptibility of Reduced, Alkylated Trypsin Inhibitors from Lima Beans to Tryptic Action" by Ferdinand, Moore, and Stein (Box 137, Folder 1203)
  - "Ultraviolet Rotary Dispersion as a Probe for the Interaction between DNA and Metal Ions" by Cheng (Box 137, Folder 1204)
  - "An Unusual Disulfide Bond in Streptococcal Proteinase" by Ferdinand, Stein, and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1205)
  - "The Use of Cyanate for the Determination of NH2-Terminal Residues in Proteins" by Stark and Smyth (Box 137, Folder 1206)
  - "The Use of Cyanate for the Determination of NH2-Terminal Residues in Proteins" by Stark and Smyth (Box 137, Folder 1207)
- Audio-Visual Materials, 1949-1982; 10
  Series 10, Audio-Visual Materials, is arranged by media, and alphabetically thereunder.
  Series 10, Audio-Visual Materials, includes photographs, negatives, slides, glass slides, audio tapes, microfiche, and film. All audio-visual media from other series within the collection have been removed to this series, and placed in a folder of the same name as the original.
  - Photographs
    - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1969 (Box 137, Folder 1208)
    - Aspartame (Box 137, Folder 1209)
    - Australia, 1965 (Box 137, Folder 1210)
    - Automatic Fraction Collector (Box 137, Folder 1211)
    - Boston and Rockefeller University Seminar, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 1212)
    - Boyer, The Enzymes (Box 137, Folder 1213)
    - Brussels, 1950-1951 (Box 137, Folder 1214)
    - Cambridge, 1951 (Box 137, Folder 1215)
    - Chicago, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 1216)
    - Christmas Lectures, 1961-1962 (Box 138, Folder 1217)
    - Christmas Lectures, 1961; 1980 (Box 138, Folder 1218)
    - Chromatograms (Box 138, Folder 1219)
    - Clippings (Box 138, Folder 1220)
    - Correspondence (Box 138, Folder 1221)
    - Lyman C. Craig (Box 138, Folder 1222)
    - Deoxyribonuclease (Box 138, Folder 1223)
    - Edman Degradation (Box 138, Folder 1224)
    - Europe, 1954 (Box 138, Folder 1225)
    - Europe, 1958 (Box 138, Folder 1226)
    - Europe, 1969 (Box 138, Folder 1227)
    - Europe, 1973 (Box 138, Folder 1228)
    - Europe, 1975 (Box 138, Folder 1229)
    - Europe, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 1230)
    - Fluorescamine and o-Phthalaldehyde (Box 138, Folder 1231)
    - France, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 1232)
    - Gas Chromatography (Box 138, Folder 1233)
    - Illustrations (Box 139, Folder 1236, Box 138, Folder 1235, Folder 1234)
    - Insulin (Box 139, Folder 1237)
    - Iowa, 1979 (Box 139, Folder 1238)
    - IUPAC and Insulin, 1955-1956 (Box 139, Folder 1239)
    - Japan, 1977 (Box 139, Folder 1240)
    - Laboratory Administration, M. Prince Brigham (Box 139, Folder 1241)
    - Laboratory Administration, Michael Bustin (Box 139, Folder 1242)
    - Laboratory Administration, Charles F. Crampton (Box 139, Folder 1243)
    - Laboratory Administration, Arthur M. Crestfield (Box 139, Folder 1244)
    - Laboratory Administration, Arthur M. Crestfield, Sample Injectors (Box 139, Folder 1245)
    - Laboratory Administration, Allen B. Edmundson (Box 139, Folder 1246)
    - Laboratory Administration, Paul L. Fletcher, Jr. (Box 139, Folder 1247)
    - Laboratory Administration, Dana Giulian (Box 139, Folder 1248)
    - Laboratory Administration, Arabinda Guha (Box 139, Folder 1249)
    - Laboratory Administration, Rikimaru Hayashi (Box 139, Folder 1250)
    - Laboratory Administration, Robert L. Heinrikson (Box 139, Folder 1251)
    - Laboratory Administration, C.H.W. Hirs (Box 139, Folder 1252)
    - Laboratory Administration, Shoshi Ota (Box 139, Folder 1253)
    - Laboratory Administration, John C. Saari (Box 139, Folder 1254)
    - Laboratory Administration, Johann Salnikow (Box 139, Folder 1255)
    - Laboratory Administration, Derek Smyth (Box 139, Folder 1256)
    - Laboratory Administration, William H. Stein (Box 139, Folder 1257)
    - Laboratory Administration, Harris H. Tallan (Box 139, Folder 1258)
    - Laboratory Administration, Glynn Wilson (Box 139, Folder 1259)
    - Laboratory Notes and Notebooks, Recorder (Box 139, Folder 1260)
    - Laboratory Notes and Notebooks, RNase on Cells [Notebook] (Box 139, Folder 1261)
    - Lectures, 1976 (Box 139, Folder 1262)
    - James M. Manning (Box 139, Folder 1263)
    - Marseille, Berlin, London, Paris, 1964 (Box 139, Folder 1264)
    - Mathematics of Distribution (Box 139, Folder 1265)
    - Stanford Moore and Family (Box 140, Folder 1266)
    - Moore Laboratory (Box 140, Folder 1267)
    - Stanford Moore, 1930s (Box 140, Folder 1268)
    - Stanford Moore, 1940s (Box 140, Folder 1269)
    - Stanford Moore, 1950s (Box 140, Folder 1270)
    - Stanford Moore, 1960s (Box 140, Folder 1271)
    - Stanford Moore, 1970s (Box 140, Folder 1271A)
    - Stanford Moore, Undated (Box 140, Folder 1272)
    - Moscow, 1976 (Box 140, Folder 1273)
    - National Institutes of Health Symposium, Bethesda, 1980 (Box 140, Folder 1274)
    - NIH, 1975 (Box 140, Folder 1275)
    - Ninhydrin (Box 140, Folder 1276)
    - Nobel Festival (Box 140, Folder 1277)
    - Nobel Prize (Box 140, Folder 1278)
    - Nobel Prize, General (Box 140, Folder 1279)
    - Oneonta, 1979 (Box 140, Folder 1280)
    - Paper Chromatograms to be Printed, William H. Stein (Box 141, Folder 1281)
    - Passport, 1949 (Box 141, Folder 1282)
    - Pepsin (Box 141, Folder 1283)
    - Population Council (Box 141, Folder 1284)
    - Portraits, 1971-1982 (Box 141, Folder 1285)
    - Recorder (Box 141, Folder 1286)
    - Ribonuclease (Box 141, Folder 1287)
    - Riga, 1976 (Box 141, Folder 1288)
    - Ri-Ry (Box 141, Folder 1289)
    - Rockefeller University Press Booklet (Box 141, Folder 1290)
    - Russian (Box 141, Folder 1291)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Circular (Box 141, Folder 1292)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, New York Convention Bureau (Box 141, Folder 1293)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Press Committee (Box 141, Folder 1294)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Program Committee (Box 141, Folder 1295)
    - Suspense File (Box 141, Folder 1296)
    - Taiwan, 1976 (Box 141, Folder 1297)
    - Tennessee and Texas, 1967 (Box 141, Folder 1298)
    - Third American Peptide Symposium (Box 141, Folder 1299)
    - Travel Documents, 1949-1981 (Box 141, Folder 1300)
    - Vanderbilt, 1968 (Box 141, Folder 1301)
    - Vanderbilt Board of Trustees (Box 141, Folder 1302)
    - Vanderbilt Visiting Professorship (Box 141, Folder 1303)
    - Visiting Professorship, Francqui Chair, Brussels, 1950-1951 (Box 141, Folder 1304)
    - Wisconsin, 1974 (Box 141, Folder 1305)
    - Wollin (Box 141, Folder 1306)
    - Z (Box 141, Folder 1307)
    - Bergmann, Moore as Child, Portraits (Box 147, Folder 1352)
    - Hayashi Album, 1972 (Box 147)
  - Negatives
    - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1969 (Box 141, Folder 1308)
    - Lyman C. Craig (Box 141, Folder 1309)
    - Illustrations (Box 141, Folder 1310)
    - Laboratory Administration, Arthur M. Crestfield, Sample Injectors (Box 141, Folder 1311)
    - Laboratory Administration, Paul L. Fletcher, Jr. (Box 141, Folder 1312)
    - Laboratory Administration, Arabinda Guha (Box 141, Folder 1313)
    - Laboratory Administration, Rikimaru Hayashi (Box 141, Folder 1314)
    - Laboratory Administration, Johann Salnikow (Box 141, Folder 1315)
    - Laboratory Administration, William H. Stein (Box 141, Folder 1316)
    - Laboratory Administration, Dalton Wang (Box 141, Folder 1317)
    - Laboratory Administration, Glynn Wilson (Box 141, Folder 1318)
    - Stanford Moore, 1930s (Box 142, Folder 1319)
    - Stanford Moore, 1940s (Box 142, Folder 1319A)
    - Stanford Moore, 1950s (Box 142, Folder 1320, Folder 1322, Folder 1321, Folder 1324, Folder 1323, Box 143, Folder 1326, Folder 1325, Folder 1327)
    - Stanford Moore, 1960s (Box 144, Folder 1333, Folder 1332, Folder 1331, Box 143, Folder 1330, Folder 1329, Folder 1328)
    - Nobel Festival (Box 144, Folder 1334)
    - Nobel Prize (Box 144, Folder 1335)
    - Nobel Prize, General (Box 144, Folder 1336)
    - Rockefeller University Board (Box 144, Folder 1337)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Circular (Box 144, Folder 1338)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Press Committee (Box 144, Folder 1339)
  - Slides
    - On Lyman Craig (Box 144, Folder 1340)
    - Hugli (Box 144, Folder 1341)
    - Laboratory Administration, Teh-Yung Liu (Box 144, Folder 1342)
    - Laboratory Notes and Notebooks, [Unlabeled Notes] (Box 144, Folder 1343)
    - Stanford Moore, Undated (Box 145, Folder 1344, Folder 1345, Folder 1346)
    - Plapp - Pictures of Model (Box 145, Folder 1347)
    - Polyspermine RNase (Box 145, Folder 1348)
    - Slides for Rikimaru Hayashi via James Manning (Box 145, Folder 1349)
    - Ta DNase and Jacques (Box 145, Folder 1350)
  - Microfiche
    - American Society of Biological Chemists, Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1969-1976 (Box 145, Folder 1351)
  - Glass Slides, 64 Item(s) (Box 146)
  - Audio Tapes
    RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    - Unlabeled Audio Reels, 6 microform reels (Box 147)
      RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    - Unlabeled Audio Tapes, 3 tapes (Box 147)
- Ephemera, 1931-1981; 11
  Series 11, Ephemera, is arranged alphabetically within each box.
  Series 11, Ephemera, contains memorabilia and other objects from the Stanford Moore Papers, including certificates, diplomas, medals, paperweights, and other such objects.
  - Book, L'Art en Belgique [removed to library] (Box 148)
  - Stanford Moore, 1972 Nobel Prize for Chemistry, Scrapbook (Box 148)
  - Name Plate (Box 148)
  - Slide Rule (Box 148)
  - Certificate, American Society of Biological Chemists, 1961 (Box 149, Folder 1353)
  - Certificate, Italica Societas Biologiae Experimentalis, 1975 (Box 149, Folder 1354)
  - Certificate, Kaj Linderstrøm-Lang Prize, 1972 (Box 149, Folder 1355)
  - Certificate, Vanderbilt University Centennial Campaign, 1981 (Box 149, Folder 1356)
  - Certificate, Vanderbilt University to Michael I. Sovern, Columbia University, 1980 (Box 149, Folder 1357)
  - Certificate, War Department and Navy Department, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 1358)
  - Chromatograms (Box 149, Folder 1359)
  - Diploma, Peabody Demonstration School, 1931 (Box 149, Folder 1360)
  - Diploma, University of Wisconsin [Honorary Degree], 1974 (Box 149, Folder 1361)
  - Stanford Moore, Model (Box 149, Folder 1362)
  - Reproduction, "Portrait of Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier and his wife" by Jacques-Louis David (Box 149, Folder 1363)
  - Telephone-Address Books (Box 149, Folder 1364)
  - Medal, "Conferenza Ernesto Scoffone, Universitas Studiipaduani" (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Kaj Linderstrøm-Lang Prize" (Box 150)
  - Medal, Nobel Prize, 1972 (Box 150)
  - Medal, Nobel Prize, 1972 (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Theodore William Richards Medal", 1972 (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Theodore William Richards Medal", 1972 (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Université Libre de Bruxelles" (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Université Libre de Bruxelles" (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Université de Liège", 1951 (Box 150)
  - Medal, "Vanderbilt University, Arts and Science", 1935 (Box 150)
  - Military Tags (Civilian), Stanford Moore (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "A Century of Science," Vanderbilt University (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "Cinquantenaire de la Societé de Chimie Biologique" (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "Fondation Universitaire/Universitaire Stichting" (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "Fonds National de la Recherche Scientifique/Nationaal Fonds voor Wetenschap Pelijk Onderzoek" (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "National Academy of Sciences Centennial", 1963 (Box 150)
  - Paperweight, "Paris-New York Air France First Flight" (Box 150)
  - Patch, "Scientific Consultant" (Box 150)
  - Pin, "ΓΑ" (Box 150)
  - Pin, "Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry" (Box 150)
  - Pocket Watch, "Phi Beta Kappa, Vanderbilt", 1935 (Box 150)
  - Decoration, "Docteur Honoris Causa de l'Université de Paris", 1964 (Box 151)
  - Clock, "Organizing Committee, Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry" (Box 152)
  - Clock, "Vanderbilt University Hospital" (Box 152)
  - Cup, Engraved with "S.M." (Box 152)
  - Medal, "Docteur Honoris Causa de l'Université de Paris", 1964 (Box 152)
  - Plaque, "Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology", 1971 (Box 152)
  - Telephone-Address Book (Box 152)
  - Plate, from K.Y. Lee and T.Y. Lee (Box 153)
  - Tools, [as per J. Manning, for repairing other lab's analyzers] (Box 153)
  - Book, from Ta-Hsiu and Tsui-Hsing, 1978 (Box 154)
  - Certificate, Nobel Prize, 1972 (Box 154)
  - Plaque, "Albany Medical College Theobald Smith Lecture", 1974 (Box 154)
  - Academic Regalia, Robe (Box 155)
  - Academic Regalia, Hoods and Decorations (Box 156)